

CONTACT

- ahmedaltakrouri@gmail.com
- **** +971585296947
- UAE Dubai
- https://ahmed-altakrouri.github.io

EXPERTISE

- Machine Learning
- Deep Learning
- Probabilistic Modeling
- Statistical Modeling
- Data Analysis
- Data Visualization
- Natural Language Processing
- Python, JavaScript.
- Libraries: Tensorflow, Keras,
 Scikit-learn, Pandas, Flask,
 XGboost, LightGBM, SHAP,
 Optuna, Plotly and Pymc4
- Cloud: Azure Databricks, Azure DataFactory, AWS, Mlfow, Airflow

AHMED ALTAKROURI

Senior Data Scientist

I solve hard problems using data. My career focus is to exploit ML/AI for business. I have over 6 years of professional experience in machine learning and data science ranging from natural language processing to forecasting models. My main interests and focus include but are not limited to: Probabilistic Machine Learning, Causal Inference, Natural Language Understanding and Bayesian Inference.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SENIOR DATA SCIENTIST

Sep 2022 - Apr 2023

Hyke.ai

- Churn prediction for purchasers.
- Purchase prediction.
- Credit risk and optimization.
- Customer segmentation for B2B.

DATA SCIENTIST

May 2021 - Sep 2022

Investment and Development Office, Government of Ras Al Khaimah.

- Churn prediction for customers of the economic zone.
- Predictive maintenance and survival modeling for machines used in mining groups.
- Uplift modeling for persuasion.

DATA SCIENTIST - CONTRACT Nov 2019 - May 2021

Orange.com

- Incoming call prediction for call center.
- Call center speech logs topics identification.
- Churn prediction for mobile subscription.
- Identifying high potential sales areas.
- Social media crawling of users' complaints.
- Crawling competitors's websites to extract their coverage areas.

DATA SCIENTIST - NLP

Nov 2017 - Nov 2019

Mawdoo3.com

- Large scale article classification model for Mowjaz.com
- Large LDA modeling for Mawdoo3.com articles ~140K.
- Emotion detection in Arabic text.
- Sentiment analysis in Arabic text.
- Intent classification.

EDUCATION

Sapienza University of Rome, Italy 2014 - 2016

Master's Degree in Artificial Intelligence and Robotics

Score (GPA: 29/30)

Applied Science University, Jordan 2006 - 2010

Bachelor of Software Engineering

PUBLICATIONS

Semantic-based retrieving model of reuse software component.

• Dr. Nedhal A. Al Saiyd ,Dr. Intisar A. Al Said ,Ahmed H. ALtakrouri · Jul 7, 2010.

Mawdoo3 Al at MADAR Shared Task: Arabic Tweet Dialect Identification.

• Bashar Talafha | Wael Farhan | Ahmed Altakrouri | Hussein Al-Natsheh Proceedings of the Fourth Arabic Natural Language Processing Workshop.

LANGUAGES

Native: Arabic

Professional Advanced Level: English

Medium Proficiency: Italian

HOBBIES

Ashtanga Vinyasa Yoga.

 Teacher and practitioner with 200 and 500 HR authorized training. Teaching Western and Indian Philosophy, holder of 4 certificates from 2 authorized international teachers.

Marathon Runner.

• Finished half marathon, currently practicing to participate in full marathon.